

Katie Gilbert

Marketing Professional

Phone: 971-212-3698 Email: ktagilbert@gmail.com Portfolio: katalogspace.com

Profile

I am a creative digital marketer with extensive content writing experience stemming from four years studying journalism and three years of content marketing experience. That, combined with indepth analytical abilities, make me uniquely qualified to drive inbound leads and create solid digital marketing strategies. Success includes a 64% increase in site traffic and 150% improvement in overall social engagement.

Skills

Social Media Marketing

Google Analytics & Google Search Console

Keyword Research

Content Creation and Content Strategy

SEO

HTML, CSS, & Markdown

Education

Seattle University - 2011-2014Bachelor of Arts, Creative Writing

School Projects:

Founder & President of Literary Society

Experience

Brandefined - Chief Content Officer June 2016 - January, 2017

I managed 70 clients and worked to improve work efficiency in the content department. To achieve my goals, I implemented new processes and workflows while also writing content for around 50 recurring clients.

- I wrote compelling website copy for custom-made WordPress sites. Websites helped our clients drive inbound leads and sales.
- · Had a 95% client retention rate.
- Wrote blog articles, press releases, social media content, and eNewsletters for clients.
- Managed a team of writers.
- Lead sprint meetings and handled scrum duties
- · Worked with clients directly to define content marketing strategies.

Velocity Marketing Partners - SEO Specialist

February 2016 - June 2016

Here, I improved campaign reporting for our SEO clients, managed 30 SEO client accounts, and shared my knowledge of SEO, social media marketing, and inbound lead generation across departments.

- · Created industry targeted lead campaigns.
- · Had a 93% client retention rate.
- Created an internal company style guide for online content.
- · Managed the team's editorial calendar.
- Wrote informative blog articles about SEO & web development.

Adpearance - Inbound Marketing Intern

November 2015 - February 2016

I worked with their automotive team to help with client facing reports, social media marketing, and copy-editing.

- Wrote social media messages for clients to improve their social media marketing efforts.
- Content was published on Facebook, Google+, LinkedIn, and Twitter for both local and national brands
- · Performed on-page SEO for automotive clients

Caring Senior Service - Digital Marketing Specialist October 2014 - June 2015

Here, I helped build & execute a digital strategy from the ground up, developed promotional campaigns for new content pieces, and was the social media manager for over 20 franchise locations.

- Increased overall social engagement by over 150%.
- Successfully increased site traffic by 64%.
- · Worked directly with franchisees.
- · Used analytics to improve digital strategy.